Nagaraj Alagusundaram



me@nagaraj.com.au



0415250335



linkedin.com/in/nalagusundaram



https://www.nagaraj.com.au

Summary

I'm a Senior Software Engineer at Xam-Consulting Pty Ltd, helping enterprise customers innovate faster with Flutter, Kotlin, Xamarin, Java & Swift.

Hands-on experience with Java, Kotlin, Android SDK, Rest APIs, Git, Dart, Flutter, and other tech principles and culture via both team/individual projects, code reviews, and pair programming.

Experienced in

- * developing a bank-level security app.
- * Implementing TDD
- * Creating pipelines from scratch for Native Android, iOS, Xamarin & Flutter projects.
- * Azure DevOps, Agile
- * Contributing to Opensource projects

Portfolio: https://www.nagaraj.com.au GitHub: https://github.com/NaagAlgates GitLab: https://gitlab.com/naag.algates

Experience

*xam Senior Software Engineer

XAM Consulting

Sep 2020 - Present (7 months +)

LINK Software Engineer (on-site via Xam Consulting)

Link Group (LNK)

Sep 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months +)

*xam Software Developer

XAM Consulting

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020 (1 year 1 month)



Software Engineer

AGAM Solutions

Mar 2019 - Sep 2019 (7 months)

Developed an app using Flutter



iCodeNext Pty Ltd

Sep 2018 - Jan 2019 (5 months)

Hired people from India to develop a product.

Tech Lead

Bahwan CyberTek

Apr 2016 - Aug 2018 (2 years 5 months)

Freelance Android App Developer

TNE Software Solutions

Apr 2015 - Mar 2016 (1 year)

U: Senior Software Engineer

UST

Nov 2013 - Mar 2015 (1 year 5 months)

Senior Software engineer - IVR

Planet41 Mobi-Venture Ltd.

Jul 2012 - Oct 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Software Engineer - Voice Developer

Nuance Communications

Jan 2012 - Jul 2012 (7 months)

Software Engineer - IVR Developement

Cellcast

Sep 2010 - Dec 2011 (1 year 4 months)

Senior Engineer

LatticeBridge Infotech Pvt. Ltd.

Jun 2008 - Aug 2010 (2 years 3 months)

Education



B.Tech, C.S.E

2004 - 2008

Kamala Subramaniam School & Trust

SSLC

2000 - 2002

Licenses & Certifications

Android (Hard) - TestDome

Issued Jul 2019 - Expires Jul 2022 883ee1b662a143c1983fd9b7c566df3f

Skills

Android • Flutter • Kotlin • Android Development • Software Development • Mobile Applications • Scrum • Agile Methodologies • Android SDK • Java

Honors & Awards



Puts the Client First - HariKrishnan Krishnakumar

Nov 2014

Most Active Contributor Award - Dave Webb

Nov 2014

Beat Team Player Award - Mohan Ram

Sep 2009

Best Team Player - 2017 - Durga Prasad

Dec 2017

Xam Social Hero - XAM

Jan 2021